export const JEWELLERYA2021 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Which of the following is a base metal?",
A: "Copper",
B: "Bronze",
C: "Gold",
D: "Silver",
answer: "A. Copper",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. he Fusing two or more metals in a crucible is referred to as",
A: "alloying.",
B: "annealing.",
C: "electroplating.",
D: "anodizing.",
answer: "A. Alloying",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. A metal jewellery is best finished by",
A: "enamelling.",
B: "pickling.",
C: "etching.",
D: "buffing.",
answer: "D. Buffing",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Choose the property which allows metals to be hammered into various shapes.",
A: "Ductility",
B: "Malleability",
C: "Elasticity",
D: "Weldability",
answer: "B. Malleability",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Cutting of gemstones is termed",
A: "forging.",
B: "electroplating.",
C: "lapidary.",
D: "repoussé",
answer: "C. Lapidary",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Choose the appropriate tool for boring holes in cane beads.",
A: "Dividers",
B: "Needle",
C: "Nail",
D: "Awl",
answer: "D. Awl",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following materials is used for alloying gold?",
A: "Platinum",
B: "Brass",
C: "Copper",
D: "Iron",
answer: "C. Copper",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The most efficient source of energy for firing a kiln is",
A: "gas.",
B: "electricity.",
C: "wood.",
D: "oil.",
answer: "B. Electricity",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. An explosion is likely to occur in a jewllery workshop when",
A: "acid is added to water.",
B: "dilute acid is added to concentrated acid.",
C: "concentrated acid is added to dilute acid.",
D: "water is added to acid.",
answer: "D. Water is added to acid",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Shrinkage in prepared clay slab for jewellery begins when it is",
A: "dried.",
B: "fired.",
C: "plastic.",
D: "porous.",
answer: "A. Dried",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The inaccessible parts of a finger ring are smoothened with",
A: "round file.",
B: "riffler file.",
C: "flat file.",
D: "knife file.",
answer: "B. Riffler file",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Careers for jewellery students include",
A: "weavers.",
B: "potters.",
C: "engravers.",
D: "printers.",
answer: "C. Engravers",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The jeweller’s scrap book is mainly used for",
A: "exhibition.",
B: "decoration.",
C: "reference.",
D: "sketching.",
answer: "C. Reference",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Identify the appropriate tool used in removing excess solder on a piece of work.",
A: "Pliers",
B: "Dividers",
C: "Scripers",
D: "Snips",
answer: "C. Scrapers",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Choose the metal which is produced from bauxite.",
A: "Aluminium",
B: "Copper",
C: "Silver",
D: "Tin",
answer: "A. Aluminium",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. A broken silver sequins can be repaired by using",
A: "mucilage.",
B: "Slip.",
C: "solder.",
D: "tragacanth.",
answer: "C. Solder",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The first step in removing verdigris on a copper ring is",
A: "annealing.",
B: "cleaning.",
C: "cooling.",
D: "pickling.",
answer: "D. Pickling",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Choose the natural material from which metals are obtained.",
A: "Gangue",
B: "Cellulose",
C: "Ore",
D: "Silica",
answer: "C. Ore",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The main objective for pickling in-between soldering is to",
A: "remove oxides.",
B: "sofien the metal.",
C: "to prevent breakage.",
D: "improve it’s colour.",
answer: "A. Remove oxides",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Identify the property of a highly polished metal wristband that enables it to reflect light.",
A: "Versatility",
B: "Ductility",
C: "Luster",
D: "Malleability",
answer: "C. Luster",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Identify the material obtained from mineral source from the options.",
A: "Bone",
B: "Ivory",
C: "Cowrie",
D: "Clay",
answer: "D. Clay",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Working continuously on an annealed sheet of metal will increase it’s",
A: "hardness.",
B: "softness.",
C: "malleability,",
D: "fusibility.",
answer: "A. Hardness",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Select the article which is finished by scorching.",
A: "Glass neck bead",
B: "Leather hair slide",
C: "Clay pendant",
D: "Copper bangle",
answer: "B. Leather hair slide",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Choose the most appropriate compound used to control acid seepage during etching.",
A: "Asphaltum",
B: "Lacquer",
C: "Mucilage",
D: "Turpentine",
answer: "A. Asphaltum",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which of these cquipment is a heating chamber for jewellery works?",
A: "Crucible",
B: "Sagger",
C: "Kiln",
D: "Incinerator",
answer: "C. Kiln",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Clay for fabricating jewellery items is wedged in order to",
A: "change it’s colour.",
B: "harden it.",
C: "remove foreign bodies.",
D: "soften it.",
answer: "C. Remove foreign bodies",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Ametal jewellery is best finished by",
A: "enamelling.",
B: "pickling.",
C: "etching.",
D: "buffing.",
answer: "D. Buffing",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. During the process of soldering flux is applied to",
A: "only the metal.",
B: "only the solder.",
C: "both blowtorch and metal.",
D: "both metal and solder.",
answer: "D. Both metal and solder",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following properties enables metals to be hammered, bent or rolled without breaking?",
A: "Malleability",
B: "Conductivity",
C: "Ductility",
D: "Fusibility",
answer: "A. Malleability",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Choose the tool used for sizing, stretching and shaping rings.",
A: "Mallet",
B: "Pliers",
C: "Mandrel",
D: "Tweezers",
answer: "C. Mandrel",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Select the activity in jewellery which requires the use of stakes.",
A: "Forging",
B: "Casting",
C: "Soldering",
D: "Enamelling",
answer: "A. Forging",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Select the most appropriate plier for forming loops in jewellery.",
A: "Round nose",
B: "Flat nose",
C: "Long nose",
D: "Half round nose",
answer: "A. Round nose",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following techniques is used in decorating bamboo jewellery?",
A: "Repoussé",
B: ", Embossing",
C: "Buffing",
D: "Smoking",
answer: "D. Smoking",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Precaution should be taken when working with acid because it is",
A: "offensive.",
B: "corrosive.",
C: "volatile.",
D: "irritating,",
answer: "B. Corrosive",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. To inscribe ares and circles on metal plates, use",
A: "scrapers.",
B: "dividers.",
C: "callipers.",
D: "drills.",
answer: "B. Dividers",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. A town in Ghana noted for metal jewellery in the Greater Accra region is",
A: "Teshie.",
B: "Ningo.",
C: "Nungua.",
D: "Dodowa.",
answer: "A. Teshie",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of these materials is used for the high polishing of precious metal ?",
A: "Emery paste",
B: "Rouge",
C: "Scratch brush",
D: "Tripoli",
answer: "B. Rouge",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Binding wires made of iron causes pickling solution to become",
A: "oily.",
B: "sticky.",
C: "strong.",
D: "weak.",
answer: "D. Weak",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. In the production of glass beads, the shape is obtained when the",
A: "glass is pounded and moulded.",
B: "glass is soft and malleable.",
C: "material is rolled to shape and fused.",
D: "mould is filled and fired.",
answer: "C. Material is rolled to shape and fused",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Identify the correct procedure for etching.\nI.Covering a metal sheet with beewax\nII. Emersing in acid solution\nIII.  Denting the metal with a punch\nIV. Designing the metal sheet with scriber",
A: "II, J, IV, III",
B: "L, IV, II only",
C: "IV, II, I,",
D: "IV, 1, Il, III",
answer: "B. I, IV, II only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]